[Music]
hello everybody
welcome to the 43rd live session of ask
a budget
today we talk about the rn invasion
theory before that before we begin let
me see who all is there
i can see uma shankar
and so many other people great to be
with you all again and thank you for
your wishes for a happy teacher's day
wish you the same
so let's talk about the aryan invasion
theory
i know this is the topic you've all been
waiting for so
let's talk about that before i take your
questions let me
share
my own history
of how i got into this particular uh
matter in history so until 2016 you'll
be surprised to know i was a firm
believer
in the aryan invasion theory
i mean i have been studying
and reading about history my entire life
and every single book i read every
single research paper or article i read
they all supported the aryan invasion
theory including books and by by indian
authors
people like baal gangada tilak
saraswati and so many others
so everybody
supported the rn invasion theory so and
and there was a great deal of scientific
evidence as well there is the genetic
evidence that links indians to uh people
from europe there is the linguistic
evidence that links india the ancient
languages of india with the modern
languages of europe and every single
researcher every single historian they
all drew the conclusion that this is an
invasion that came from eastern europe
or central asia into india and into
europe
and this is how we have these
connections
so i saw no reason to not believe it
because everybody every eminent
historian every scientist they all
unanimously agreed with this theory
and i was aware
that there were certain
indian voices that were in opposition to
this theory i had heard about this out
of india theory and i frankly found it
embarrassing
my attitude was very simple we know that
we are that humanity came out of africa
so how does it matter
that whether there was an invasion from
by the aryans from europe or not we are
all migrants
so why do we have to oppose everything
why do why do indians especially
especially hindu nationalists have to
say that everything came out of india
that was my
position on this i found this opposition
to the aryan invasion theory very
embarrassing
right
now then what happened is that i
recently came across some new research
about
an invasion of europe that happened
about five thousand years ago so there
was this bunch of horse-riding men
extremely violent men who invaded europe
from the east
about 5 000 years ago and they committed
an absolute genocide in europe they
wiped out every single european male
and
they took all the females as their
reproductive partners
and in a very brief period of time the
entire older
european male genetics were wiped out
and today's europeans are the
descendants of these new invaders from
5000 years ago and the older european
women so so i i saw this this research
let me show you some i have spoken about
this before so this is one of the
headlines the most violent group of
people who ever lived
horse riding yamnaya tribe used their
huge height
in
build to brutally murder and invade
their way across europe more than four
thousand years ago
so this is one headline this is another
headline the most murderous people of
all time revealed in ancient dna this
was a violent conquest of europe and
genetic analysis tells the tale for the
first time this was from 2019 but this
news started coming in in research
papers from 2015 i think onwards
here's one more stored age genocide
vengeful prehistoric invaders who
changed europe forever so essentially we
find this sudden shift in european
genetics it's a clear indication of
genocide
wide scale genocide the entire genetic
makeup
the petri linear lineages change
overnight almost in europe so this is a
sudden influx of foreign genes and of
course there is there is a corresponding
change in in the kind of pottery and uh
cultural artifacts that you have so
everything changed all of a sudden not
just the genetics but also the pottery
also the cultural artifacts also the
kind of uh
burial goods you have the kind of burial
rituals you have and all that and also
you find this widespread evidence of
massacres as you can see this is a mass
grave a number of people dumped together
into a pit and buried history without
any ceremony without any respect so
these are
the older the original europeans who
were massacred in enormous quantities by
these new horse riding invaders okay
so i
found this very interesting that this
sort of thing had happened in europe and
i also found
that these same yamnaya invaders were
supposed to have brought the aryan genes
into india
right
so i found this very curious i found it
very interesting and therefore i
researched it further i started recently
researching the genetic data that we
have i started researching the other all
the other kinds of evidence
and
i found something very surprising let me
let me share another thing with you
so once i started looking into the
genetics i found very interesting and
very surprising
things i found that
when the out of africa migration
happened
the first place where humanity settled
down was
india and and more than 90 percent of
the entire world's entire
world's non-african males
have
are descended from an ancient indian
patrilineal genetic lineage haplogroup f
so more than 90 percent of all
non-african men who are alive in the
world today
are descended from an ancient indian
genetic lineage haplogroup f this is a
patrilineal lineage which originated
about
about 60 65 000 years ago
in india
i also discovered after that that more
than 95 percent of all
non-african women who are alive in the
world today are also descended from two
or three indian genetic lineages
haplogroup m n and r which
the oldest of which arose in india
between 65 and 75 000 years before today
so so this tells us that india was the
original founders zone foundation zone
of the out of africa movement it is from
india that all other non-african
populations were populated so india is
the ancestral region of all almost all
non-african humans today
i found this very surprising then i
researched some more
ancient genetic genetic papers i found
that there is almost no there is
completely negligible
gene flow from outside into india in the
past 10 15 000 years
negligible
when we talk about the yamnaya invasion
of europe that's a complete replacement
event
the male genetics are wiped out and a do
replacement genetics is put in so that
there is the
invasion of europe but in the case of
india
there is no such replacement event the
gene flow from outside is completely
negligible in the past 10 15 000 years
i also found that the uh
many genetic studies have have
demonstrated that north india and south
india have essentially the same genetics
right you see the the distance between
northern india let's say kashmir or
afghanistan and southern india is more
than 3000 kilometers
it's an enormous subcontinent
the distance between sweden and greece
is less than that
and the people of sweden look very
different from the people of greece
right
so similarly in india also we have this
enormous genetic diversity but all it's
a very ancient
some 60 70 000 year old ancient genetic
population and that's why there is so
much diversity in facial features in
height in skin color in eye color hair
color and all that
right then i also found that the indus
valley civilization
is the oldest known civilization of all
time
the oldest continuously existing
civilization in its cultural traits are
still present in india today what we
call hinduism was was practiced five six
thousand years ago in the sindhu region
there is so much evidence of cultural
continuity so if there was an invasion
into india how come this culture was not
destroyed and there was a cultural
discontinuity like we find in europe
and then where is the evidence of the
massacres
if there was a yamnaya invasion into
india
and we know how brutal they were and we
know
what they did in europe we know the
genocide they perpetrated in europe we
know all the mass graves and destruction
so why is it not seen in india
where is it right
and so these are some of the things that
tell us that there is something very
fishy about this ideal invasion theory
so we have evidence of cultural
continuity there is zero evidence of an
invasion there is zero evidence of a
migration and there is layer upon layer
of archaeological genetic linguistic
literary geological hydrological and all
kinds of evidence that shows that india
has been continuously inhabited by the
same population for more than 60 70 000
years
so all of this taken together shocked me
completely it shook my entire whatever i
believed until then and after this after
seeing the actual scientific data i have
come to the very firm conclusion that
the out of india theory is much more
viable and much more consistent with the
facts than any aryan invasion or
migration or tourism or picnic theory
so that is
why
after seeing the evidence after seeing
the factual evidence after studying it
for a very long time i came to the
conclusion that this aryan invasion
theory is completely fake and after
after seeing all this
i wrote an article in 2017
so this is the article i wrote it's in
indiafacts.com the title of the article
is aryan invasion myth how 21st century
science debunks 19th century indology
so this is an article i published in
2017 in which i have given an entire
detailed analysis
of all the evidence that was available
till 2017
about all these facts about all these
aspects of the iron invasion that that
are completely disproved by various
scientific and other other evidence
so it's a reasonably detailed article i
would recommend that if you're
interested you should all
go through this
so this is the first article that i know
of that puts everything together in one
place nowadays of course there are many
more people who are investing their time
into this and we have much more evidence
that's coming out but as far as i know
after all my details study this this 27
artic 2017 article is the first article
that puts everything together in one
place so this is everything that i found
until that time of course i have done
more research
uh subsequent to this uh to the
publication of this article
uh so so
that is something i would recommend you
people read now let me show you
something
else
right something uh
something that's a little more
interesting so these yamnaya people that
we spoke about
we spoke about these people who invaded
europe their facial reconstructions were
done they found uh
they found these skeletons of these
invaders and this is what the
reconstructions look like as you can see
these are reasonably european looking
people right tall strong sturdy look at
the face it is a european looking face
this is another one
another european looking individual
young man strong man look at this person
european looking person but these are
all ancient
uh reconstructions from many many years
ago
today with more genetic information with
more genetic data we know more details
about these invaders of europe
we know what was their skin color we
know what was their hair color we know
what was their eye color
and after knowing these more these
additional details
newer facial reconstructions have been
done
of the men
who changed the genetics of europe
forever and this is what their
reconstructions accurate reconstructions
look like
take a look at this guy
this is an individual found in volgograd
oblast russia yamnaya culture bronze age
about four and a half five thousand
years ago
this is an invader of europe invader of
russia these are the peop these are the
ancestors of today's europeans this is
one individual here is another
individual
this is from again from volgograd
volgograd oblast russia yamnaya culture
this is the third individual
this is from astarhan oblast in russia
these are all korgan burials grave
yamnia graves these are the invaders
who are the ancestors of more than 90
more than 90 of european men today these
guys
and here is a composite of b3 so my
friends please tell me something
if you were to see these fine gentlemen
walking on a street today
what is the first ethnicity that would
come to your mind
do they look like
russians do they look like ukrainians
do they look like swedes do they look
like europeans do they look like
africans do they look like chinese
what ethnicity comes to your mind when
you see these fine gentlemen
to my mind there's only one ethnicity
that comes to mind these guys are here
are indians
if you see them today they would the
first thing that would come to your mind
is that these guys are indians
so these are this is what these invaders
of europe look like they invaded europe
from the east
5000 years ago it was a violent barbaric
invasion these were young horse-riding
men average six feet height strong
muscular
and they just rampaged across europe and
changed the entire genetics of europe
they killed every single every last
european man
and
they took the european women as their
wives or partners and today's europeans
are descended from these fine gentlemen
so tell me now
what which version of the invasion
theory is correct right
it's very clear what's happening here so
so this is just a brief introduction
this is i'm not doing a detailed
presentation today i just wanted to see
what questions you had about this uh rn
invasion matter so that i can understand
what is your perspective about this
that's why i've invited questions and
i'm gonna answer your questions now in
the future i will do most likely a
detailed presentation about this entire
thing so now let's start with the
questions
okay anurag nag says what is the aryan
invasion theory and what are the claims
of this aryan migration and
tourism etc theory
okay let me share my screen once again
uh where are we
i'm gonna share my own article and i'm
gonna read out from there
okay so
the orient invasion theory has its
central thesis the central claims has
three three components
the first com the first claim is that
india's original inhabitants were dark
skinned dravidians
who were who built a very peaceful
highly developed urban civilization
in western and northern india presented
pakistan afghanistan the so-called
harappan or indus valley civilization
let's claim number one claim number two
is that india was invaded and conquered
from the west by a nomadic people called
the aryans or indo-aryans around 1500 bc
these indo-aryans were of european
origin they were they were white-skinned
people and they spoke vedic sanskrit and
they practiced hinduism so they
destroyed the indigenous dravidian
civilization they subjugated the natives
and forced them to migrate to the south
of india that's claim number two
and claim number three is that these
aryan invaders then composed the vedas
and imposed this evil hinduism and the
barbaric caste system upon these poor
dravidians and other indigenous people
of india
so that is the core
of the central claims
of the aryan invasion or migration
theory
that's what it is but even deeper
this theory actually has a deeper
purpose it
it it claims
that hinduism and sanskrit are foreign
to india that is the real claim
that hinduism is foreign to india
sanskrit is foreign to india these are
the religion and
and language of of
invaders
and because this is an invasive foreign
thing it should be wiped out essentially
okay so that is the real claim of the
orientation theory that is the deeper
claim and the deeper purpose of the rn
invasion theory
question two
why is the aryan invasion theory used as
a dividing tool when there is not a
single piece of evidence of any mass
violence or invasion
why is it a point of contention even if
there was a peaceful migration a very
long time ago literally all humans came
from africa this is from shivang so yeah
this that's what the the claim is it is
a dividing tool we all know
that the british had this long-standing
policy of divide and rule divide and
conquer
we know it and yet we allow it to divide
us this is a british invention it's a
european invention
it is the invention of christian
missionaries they found that indus
hindus would not convert to christianity
and therefore they started creating the
they started engineering these
artificial divisions
in india's society by dividing indians
into black and white brown and light
brown hindu and non-hindu aryan and
dravidian adivasi and god knows what
else
it is a tool of colonialism
and today it is a tool of neocolonialism
if you think that the age of colonialism
is over please think again
we are still in the age of colonialism
we are in the age of 21st century data
driven
technology driven colonialism
and this is the major tool that is used
for that in india to divide indians
the claim that sanskrit is foreign to
india the claim that hinduism is foreign
to india the claim that these foreign
invaders came into india and imposed a
caste system on the people of india all
these claims are fake but it is
very successful today so many indians
believe in this absurd theory i mean
i've seen all your questions i know many
of you actually believe it or some of
you actually think it may possibly be
true i do not blame you for it and that
is why i'm here
today i'm going to answer your questions
in the future i'm going to do a detailed
presentation on how all of this is fake
but the purpose is to divide indian
society against itself divide not from
south hindu from non-hindu they are now
inducing indians
especially those who are identified as
dalits
those who are identified as people from
southern india they're inducing these
people to give up hinduism and adopt
foreign religions
right so this is the purpose it's a
dividing tool it is it is it is it was
devised to divide and fragment india's
society and in the 21st century it has
been weaponized even further india's own
education system teaches this as the
gospel truth india's uh
i have seen certain
government websites even today that uh
support the arid invasion theory and
they present it as a fact i know that
india's judiciary talks about aryan
dravidian
invasion and all that so india is a
deeply deeply mentally colonized country
it is not the fault of indian people
that they are mentally colonized but we
need to arm ourselves with the true
knowledge and that's that is the main
point here
i don't know what the name is uh who are
these aryans and from where did this
theory of aryan invasion come so there
are no aryans there are no dravidians
these are fake categories there are only
indians india is the oldest population
group in the entire world outside of
africa
indians our ancestors have lived on the
subcontinent for 70 around 60 to between
65 and 70 000 75 000 years
and it's a very ancient population like
i said and there are no aryans or
dravidians it's a very diverse
population group with still very uniform
genetics that's the uh
that's the paradox of india
so there are no audience first of all
now where did this theory of aryan
invasion come from that's a good
question so it all started
okay
so it's not if
it's better to look at the bigger
picture when we talk about how did this
theory of aryan invasion come about and
to understand how this theory was
constructed we have to go back a
thousand years
before the british came to india so a
thousand years before today
india was
while india had not yet fallen prey to
the foreign turkic and other invasions
of india india a thousand years ago had
its own universities hundreds of
universities hundreds of wonderful
libraries
and in these libraries we had the
records of thousands of years of our
history
now this turkic invaders came into india
they destroyed every single library they
destroyed every single university they
burned every library they massacred
every single scholar every monk every
big show every guru everybody was
massacred all these teachers students
everyone was massacred
we know what happened in nalanda
but several
tens of thousands of students were
massacred in one day beheaded
the university was destroyed it was
ruined the library was burned it burned
for several months so imagine how many
how much knowledge we lost we lost all
the written records of our past we lost
the written records of thousands of
years of our past it is not just nalanda
it is so many other libraries
sharda pete vikramshila udantapuri and
so and so forth
so we lost all the written records of
our past
then the europeans came to india about
500 years before today and when they
came into india and they started taking
over parts of the country
they said you bloody indians don't have
any written history
you don't write history you know you
people just get transmitted orally
you're barbaric you're primitive you're
backward
so all of the history that you claim to
have had it's just a myth because there
is no written record so the british
deemed
all of india's oral history which was
left behind because our written history
was gone so that's why indians were
forced to pass it on orally whatever
they remembered the british came to
india and they said
that all your oral history is mythology
and then they proceeded to write their
own version of india's history
so that is the genesis of this entire
problem
now when the europeans came to india
they they
noticed
striking similarities between the
vocabulary of sanskrit and the
vocabulary of various european languages
like greek latin etc
so this became a field of study they
called it the indo-european languages
sanskrit was clearly the oldest language
they knew
so at that time they were clearly of the
opinion that it all came from india it
all came from sanskrit
then in the 19th century or 18th century
onwards
thereabouts thereabouts
the missionaries started pouring into
india european missionaries christian
missionaries
and they wanted to convert the
population of india to christianity but
it did not work
indians were very strong in their
in their culture they had a very strong
belief and pride in their culture it was
not possible to induce indians to
convert so then people like max miller
they started studying sanskrit
and max mueller the he he came up with
this new theory
based on biblical genealogy
of an invasion of people into india he
said that there were two aryan races
who lived somewhere in eastern europe or
their somewhere there and there were two
invasions one into india and iran and
the other one into europe
and he said that the european aryans
were more civilized more superior
and the indian iranian aryans were
slightly inferior but they were still
stronger than the natives and that's why
they were able to subjugate the
dravidians and take over the country and
then they impose hinduism in the caste
system and all that so this is an
invention of max miller and he said that
this happened after 1500 a.d
because of biblical chronology
chronology genealogy all that according
to the bible the world began around 4
000 years ago according to the old
testament or something like that i don't
know what it is i've never read it
but according to these christian
theories or christian myths
the world began about 4 000 or so years
ago and therefore all chronology had to
be after that
so max miller said that the rn invasion
of india happened around 1500
bc
and that's what it was right
so that was what max miller did
after that there were more individuals
who proceeded to
to
put forth more theories or let me show
you
uh one of these individuals was a person
called
herbert
hope risely
okay this is this this guy was an
exponent of scientific racism
so he said that based on the size of the
nose of indians and all there are two
races in india
so he essentially uh sought to
take what max miller had postulated and
give it some scientific basis scientific
racist bases so he said they were so
this guy herbert reisley he said there
were two races in india an aryan race
and dravidian race based on the color of
the skin and the shape of the nose and
all of that
so he's one of the founders of the aryan
dravidian myth
the second person who did this
the second individual who did this was a
christian missionary his name was bishop
robert caldwell
he is the person
who
put forth the
myth of the dravidian language family
he said that tamil and certain other
southern indian languages are a separate
language family and he gave them he gave
this language family the dravidian name
so these are dravidian languages he is
the originator of this myth of the
dravidian languages
and oh i mean
so he is
essentially
he was able to divide india in this
manner and he was able to convert some
people to christianity
he is called a scholar of the tamil
language the dravidian political parties
owe a lot to this person as you can see
there is a statue of this individual
robert caldwell
in in chennai marina beach tamil nadu
there is a church that this individual
built
somewhere in the south of india and so
on so this individual robert
caldwell is the father of the dravidian
movement the dravidian separatist moment
individuals like that person watches
them rama swami periyar and all these
dmk ai dmp all these political parties
their entire ideology
and their the justification for their
brand of politics comes from this person
so these
political parties are soft separatist
political parties they are
tamil supremacist and dravidian
supremacist political parties they claim
that they have been victimized for
several thousand years
the people of south india and therefore
they need to rise up again against the
brahmanism and hinduism and aryanism and
all that so this person robert caldwell
and the other guy robert hope risely
these are the racist individuals who
created this artificial divides in india
that other individual robert reisley
actually uh
he went further
he did one of the first censuses in
india and he categorized indians into
four categories four artificial hard
categories and this is the
beginning of the institutionalizing into
institutionalization of this british
created caste system in india india had
a very much older and much more
complicated
system called the varnajati system there
were so many different occupations so
many jyati's and these were all fluid
you could move from one jauti and one
one verna into another but these people
on the basis of all these false theories
created the four
divisions in indian society which are
today set in stone because of the
policies of the government of india
after independence
so this is
another piece of the puzzle
about the aryan invasion theory
and then all the indian academics in the
indian education system they started
teaching all this as fact
and so on and so forth this was
continued and this is essentially in
short the birth of the aryan invasion
theory this is how this theory was set
in stone and after independence india's
education system kept on teaching this
because the great british masters had
given us this great theory so how can we
disregard it so it is still taught even
today
and today we have this new
neocolonization the of the 21st century
so you have all these marxist historians
who whose objective is to wipe out
hinduism from india
and there are certain other people also
the m4
complex mullah marxist missionary media
so they all propagate this theory and
because of that because of the ubiquity
of this theory everywhere whether it's
in the movies whether it's in the social
media whether it is in the news whether
it's the judiciary the indian academia
everywhere this theory is portrayed as
the only valid theory and therefore all
indians from their childhood grow up
believing this because this is what we
are taught this is what every person in
a position of authority teaches us and
that's why
this theory continues to be taught now
in the 20th century they discovered that
there is no exis evidence of an invasion
there is no massacre there's no warfare
there's nothing and there is no evidence
of a migration also
and yet so now they are trying to give
it some genetic basis they first changed
it from invasion to migration soon it
will become tourism eventually it will
become a picnic theory
but they will anyhow try to keep it
alive so that is the
genesis and the history of the
aryan invasion migration theory
abhishek says was why was it necessary
for europeans to create this aryan
people did it have anything to do with
their own history so europeans were the
conquerors of the world they had wiped
out
the people of southern
of the americas
right they had conquered and destroyed
completely africa and they were in the
process of conquering and destroying
india and other parts of asia so there
were these all-conquering heroes
and they saw themselves as a superior
people
now when they discovered all this
evidence of the sanskrit language being
the oldest language they knew and so on
and so forth it was clear that
their ancestors actually came from india
and this hurt them a lot because i mean
they had this belief in their racial
superiority they had a belief in the
superiority of their white skin
and therefore they sought to po to put
forth a euro-centric version of history
and they had to to
also divide indian society
so they wanted to to portray this theory
to to put for this theory that hinduism
and sanskrit are foreign to india
so since your religion and language are
foreign to india
therefore it is justifiable for a new
foreign religion and language to come
into india whether it is christianity
and in english or various other
abrahamic religions
so they essentially sought to say that
since you they yourselves are the
descendants of barbaric invaders who who
oppressed the other people of india the
original people of india and therefore
it is completely justified for us to
come and oppress you now and therefore
you should give up your hinduism because
it is the religion of oppressors and
take our more enlightened christianity
and our more enlightened english
language because it is our language our
religion it is superior to yours so
these are some of the
uh
reasons why this theory was created and
even today
it is still
being pushed
today they are trying to use the science
of genetics
to claim this theory is is valid there
are all these eurocentric geneticists
and historians whether it's in the
united states whether it's in germany
who today also
are trying
to promote this theory
right but unfortunately the data does
not
prove does not bear them out so this in
short is the eurocentric racist
the reasons
why these people created this are in
aryan invasion theory first of all to
portray themselves as superior and
higher
and secondly to divide india's society
and to justify the conquest of india
their subjugation of india
and their attempts to
to convert the people of india to
christianity and to various other
abrahamic religions so that's why this
theory was necessary for them
prayag says what are the main reasons
behind the disappearance of the
saraswati river and how is it associated
with
debunking the aryan invasion theory
so uh
until
10 20 years ago until 10 or 15 years ago
every indian historian every indian
scientist would claim every
other foreign historian also would claim
that the saraswati river is just a myth
it's a myth these stupid hindus have
created there is no such river it's all
mythology
but then it clearly emerged that there
is indeed an enormous dry riverbed in
western india which starts from the
himalayas and goes all the way to the
so called arabian sea
yeah
this dry riverbed does exist it is
visible in satellite images it is an
enormous river wider and greater than
the in than the sindhu in this river and
greater than any other river in the
suburbs in the region so it is clear
that this river exists where exactly
where our so-called myths said it
existed
so it does exist now it is
these people no longer make the claim
it's a mythological river it is there
and now even in scientific journals like
nature etc people are have begu
scientists have begun calling it the
saraswati river in research papers
so now it is established beyond any
doubt this river existed
now it is known that this river dried
out around
1500 bc or thereabouts plus or minus 500
years so it dried out around the time
why did it dry out
it dried out because of the
because of the gradual decline of the
indian monsoon that's number one and
maybe also because of some seismic event
in the himalayas so the indian monsoon
about six seven eight thousand years ago
was was much heavier than what it is
today
and it is this monsoon this extremely
heavy indian mons indian monsoon that
fed the saraswati river
it was an enormous river enormous river
very powerful very very strong river so
it was fed by the indian monsoon it was
its origin was in the himalayas so it
was fled by glacial melt water from the
himalayas but as it came downwards
southwards it was felt it was fed by the
indian monsoon rains and that's why it
was such a great river enormous river
now about 6000 bce
and thereabouts and after that the
indian monsoon started declining in over
two three four thousand years it
declined so much that this river went
half dry
and it became a seasonal river and
eventually dried out in much of its
river bed
even today
it does exist in northern india it is a
seasonal river it is called the gagar
river
gagar
river you can check out my article in
which i have given the details
so that is the reason behind the
disappearance of the saraswati river the
main reason is the decline of the indian
monsoon and there could also have been
some seismic event in the himalayas
which is a seismically active zone which
may have diverted its source so these
are some of the reasons the primary
reason the major reason is the decline
of the indian monsoon now how is this
river associated with debugging
debunking the aryan inversion theory
so one of the main central claims
of the aryan invasion theory is that the
the invasion happened around 1500 bc
and the rig vedas
was written after that so the
accepted date of the writing of the
rigveda
by all mainstream eminent historians
is about 1300 bc
definitely after 1500 1500 bc
so according to this theory according to
all these wonderful mainstream
historians the rig veda was written
about 1500 or 1300 bce not before that
100 not before that
now here's the funny thing in the rig
way that there is there are so many
mentions of the saraswati river
there are entire sections devoted to
this river there are so many mentions of
this river
and the way this river is described is
striking
this river is called the mother of
floods
it is called a loudly roaring river
it is depicted as an enormous mighty
river that could destroy
surrounding regions it was the mother of
floods it was a
loudly roaring river
so the depiction of this river in the
rigveda
is clearly the depiction of an enormous
river in its prime
it is not the depiction of a river that
is declining or which has gone half dry
or a seasonal river
it is a depiction of an enormous river
in its prime
and the last time this river was in its
prime was about 6000 bc
8 000 years before today
so how did this book
that was written in 1500 or 1300 bc
remember events from 6000 bc and why was
it depicting those events it was as if
they were happening when the book was
written
this is something that our
invasion theorists can never explain
so this clearly demonstrates
that the rig veda the oldest literature
that is written in in
indian
history the oldest known literature in
the world is rigveda it is clear
that this
literature the rig weather was written
when the saraswati was in its prime and
the last time it was in its prime was
around 6000 bc
so the rig weather is clearly a book
that was written closer to 6000 bc than
to 1500 bc and this completely
demolishes the aryan invasion theory
because this is the central claim one of
the central claims
of the aryan invasion theory
so this is how the saraswati and and how
it disappeared and when it was last in
its prime this is in a way
quite central to debunking this fake
claim of the red invasion
so you can read my article and check it
out i mean i've given some details about
that in there
achin says how can human civilization
have all come from india when it has
been demonstrated that humans came from
africa and developed civilizations
everywhere also how do you state that
the out of india theory is superior to
the rn invasion theory when it hasn't
been demonstrated in a peer-reviewed
scientific paper
please let me know i would love to be
proven wrong so i also had the same
questions right like i said
i mean how does it matter where we came
from after all humans came from came
from africa see the
point of the aryan invasion theory is
not to say where we came from it is to
portray hinduism and sanskrit as being
foreign to india as the language and
this religion of invaders and oppressors
now i have already given you so much
evidence
that demonstrates
that this theory is completely fake
right and i have never made the claim
that all human civilization came from
india it is clear from all the best
evidence that we have today the best
scientific data that we have today it
demonstrates that there was an out of
africa migration about 75 000 years
before today
and the best evidence that we have also
demonstrates that the first founders
zone outside of africa was india
so i have never made the claim that
human civilization came from india
right
and
why is the out of india theory superior
to the aryan invasion theory it hasn't
been demonstrated in a peer-reviewed
scientific paper so there is no single
scientific paper that talks about the rn
invasion theory or the out of india
theory there are all these scientific
papers are individual data points it's
only when we take all of these data
points together
that we form a big picture which
completely disproves the rn invasion
theory but if you want to see one image
that
that demonstrates that the out of india
theory is correct
then let me show you
that one image
this
is the image of the invaders who are the
ancestors of more than 90 percent of
europe's men
who are alive today
what do these individuals what do these
fine gentlemen look like do they look
like europeans
qed i rest my case
okay next question
okay two questions in one excuse me
hersh says even we all indians are the
same
then why do we have such different
diverse facial characteristics the other
question is that if we are all the same
people in india how did racial facial
differences arise between north and
south and the northeast
see india is not a small geographical
region it is an enormous subcontinent
the distance between kashmir and
in the tip of southern india is greater
than the distance between sweden and
greece
it's an enormous geographical region
india is the original foundation zone of
the out of india migration it is the
oldest known population that we know of
who have been living in one region
continuously because it is around 70 000
years old there is bound to be so much
genetic diversity
within this geographical region within
this enormous subcontinent sized
geographical region and yet because it
is the same population for 70 000 years
there is an enormous amount of diversity
as well so the climate in northern india
is very different from the climate in
southern india
so people who have been living
uh families who have been living in
northern india for several thousand
years they are bound to have lighter
skin
and families who are living in southern
india are bound to have darker skin
because they have been living for
thousands of years
similarly east west these regional
uh
differences in in features skin color
hair color eye color facial features are
bound to happen and yet genetic evidence
demonstrates that there is no genuine
there is no
actual difference
there is no significant difference in
the genetics
between the people of north india and
south india now when it comes to the
north east of india that is a different
story there have been several migrations
from eastern asia
into the northeast of india people of
tibet of bourbon origin pivot of people
of synod tibetan origin and so on uh
migrations from the yunnan region of
of uh eastern asia
migrations from uh burma in the thai
territories thailand etc of of eastern
southeastern asia so these are
genetically slightly different
populations but those are also
descendants of the original ancestral
founders zone which was in india but
because they've been away for so many
thousands of years their
morphological characteristics changed
somewhat and that's why you see these uh
different features in the northeast of
india but even if you look at the
genetic lineages in northeast of india
you do find the indian origin r1 a1a
even in manipur and other places
right so it's a very complex scenario
the northeast is a special case because
there have been so many migrations into
the northeast from eastern asia that's
why they look different but still there
is a significant ancestral indian
genetic component even in northeast of
india
so that is the reason why there are so
many facial and skin color and hair
color and eye color differences
all over india because it is a very very
very large geographical region it looks
small on the map we are used to it but
if you compare it with europe you'll see
the enormity of the indian geography and
that's why because of this because of
the incredible antiquity of the indian
population and because of the incredible
size of the indian geography that's why
you have all these local regional
variations within the overall uniformity
of india's genetics
vishal says can you please
can you please explain the rakhi curry
dna analysis and what does it add to the
aryan invasion migration etc theory
so around 2015 16 or so they discovered
one a number of skeletons in the in the
in the rakigari archaeological site in
northern
northwestern india
and the and the samples dna samples of
of a number of these skeletons were
extracted they were sent for analysis
see the thing in india is that the the
climate of india the temperature etc the
humidity is such that it is very hard
for ancient dna to survive
and that's why we have not been able to
found so find
uh
a great deal of ancient indian dna in
india but nevertheless they were able to
extract dna from one one single skeleton
out of all these this dna was sequenced
analyze etc and because of that we have
now the first evidence of one individual
of the dna of one ancient indian
individual who happened to be a female
so she is one of our ancient ancestors
right so what does the dna tell us it
tells you that there is no step
component in this person step means the
eurasian step between central asia and
eastern europe and all that so these uh
there is no yamnaya kind of ancestry in
this individual it is a pure indian
ancestry
no step component the second thing that
they were able to find is that this
individual this female she had a
component of ancestry
that is
closely related to the ancestors of the
iranian people
so one of the uh beliefs is that the
iranians came westwards and invaded
india and that's why there is this
common
dna between india and iran you i i'm not
sure if you know but india and iran are
essentially the same population so the
same ancient population
the
closest ethnic
uh relatives of the iranians are indians
they aren't the arabs
so india and iran is essentially the the
descendants of the same ancient
population so the belief was that it was
these iranians who invaded india and
that's why
we have this commonality of ancestry
commonality of genetics but from the
rakhigarh skeleton it was found
that she had a component of ancestry
that was
ancestral
to the iranian populations
so the rakigari skeleton is about four
or five thousand years old and the
ancestry which was shared with the
iranians
is about 10 000 years old
so it it shows that the iranians
essentially are descendants of ancient
indians and not whites vice versa
the other thing that was found from the
jarakiri analysis is that there were
that
there are a number of ancient other
individuals other ancient individuals
who have been found in iran in
turkmenistan ancient skeletons whose dna
has been analyzed it was found that this
individual
is genetically genetically very close
to those individuals who are found in
iran and in turkmenistan they are called
indus periphery individuals and this is
evidence of an out of india migration
out of the indus valley region migration
into iran and turkmenistan so again this
supports the out of india theory
and there are many other data points
that i don't remember exactly in detail
but you can check out the article
check out the research paper and you can
see all the details so essentially what
it tells you is that there was no
uh rn invasion into india but there is
significant evidence of out of india
migrations from just the analysis of
analysis of one single individual now we
have to be very clear about this
we only have dna from one individual
it does not represent an entire
population
at its peak the sindhu region the indus
valley harappan region had a population
of over 5 million individuals which was
the greatest largest population in the
whole of the ancient world
five million it's an enormous population
for that time
so one individual does not give us is
not representative of a large population
like 5 million what we need is we need
to find more ancient uh
samples of dna
at least 10 20 30 maybe 100 200 then we
will be able to actually confidently
make a claim as to what sort of genetic
makeup was there in ancient india in in
that time period but from the one sample
that we have at our disposal it is
already showing us that there is
evidence of out of india migration and
there is no evidence of any invasion of
migrant or migration into india from
this one limited sample
so i am i need to make it very clear
that we need more samples one sample it
does not tell us the whole story but
from the limited data that we have it's
clear there was out of india migrations
okay nagendra says what do you make of
the book by tony joseph there seems to
be a lot of effort by some people to
make the aryan invasion a final
conclusion
yes so that i i you know i don't like to
talk about individuals
i like to talk about uh facts and ideas
and on
theories and all that
but in this case i'll make an exception
because tony joseph has written a book
which
which which tries to support the work of
david like and other geneticists in
claiming that there were waves of
multiple pizza-like migrations into
india and all that
so what do i think of this book is a
good question let me
so let me share my own article i had i
have done a book review of this and i
think in 2019
here is the article it is in
indiafacts.com the title is journalist
attempts to revive the rn invasion myth
using discredited genetic research it is
a reasonably detailed
article that i have written as you can
see i am the author
so
i will not go into detail about what i
think of this book
about this new work that was published
this book that was published but i would
invite you
to read
this article that i wrote a detailed
analysis of the book and its claims
and essentially to make it short to to
tell you what i think of it it's all
nonsense
it is another attempt to manif to
manipulate and cherry pick data points
and to manipulate history and to claim
that this thing happened because their
entire
their entire agenda depends on the
success of this theory
so the title should tell you what i
think of it journalist attempts to
revive
aryan invasion myth using discredited
genetic research please read the article
you will get an idea of what i think
about this and you will also learn
something about
how these people
manipulate the facts to to present false
conclusions
okay ayush says if there was no
migration or invasion by audience what
could be the reason behind the decline
of the harappan civilization this is a
good question uh so like i said it's
closely
tied to what happened to the saraswati
so the saraswati dried out over several
thousand years
because of the monotonal decline of the
indian monsoon over several thousand
years the indian monsoon was at its peak
around 6000 bc which is about 8 000
years before today
and it started declining gradually
gradually gradually over hundreds and
thousands of years and by 1500 bc
it had declined so much that the entire
great river saraswati dried out
it became seasonal and intermittent only
in the north of india where it still
exists to some extent but the great
river dried out
and so it is an example of ancient
climate change
so because of this climate change
because the conditions changed so much
the lifestyle that these
our ancient ancestors had in this region
became unsustainable
and there were so many there are
thousands of ancient archaeological
sites cities towns villages on the banks
of this dry riverbed of the saraswati
because and this river sustained
these towns villages and cities and
because the river dried out they this
was no longer sustainable
and the same thing happened in other
places also
climate change the whole lifestyle was
no longer sustainable and therefore
slowly slowly slowly
over centuries people migrated out of
this region and where and went elsewhere
this
coincided coincides with the discovery
of indian genetics in australia
about four four and a half thousand
years ago precisely coincides with that
this also coincides with the yamnya
invasion of europe
so this climate changed
change
made it necessary for indians of that
region to migrate in different
directions some of them seem to have
gone westwards on a rampage across
europe some of them seem to have
migrated by sea all the way to australia
and the majority of the population went
eastwards
into the ganga yamuna plain in other
parts of india so this was a very
gradual
dispersal
of the population of this region into
other parts
of the neighboring region some even went
into iran
there is this ancient marhashi
kingdom we know that the the king rimosh
of babylonia of mesopotamia actually
fought with the people of india of the
indus valley
region and so on
so there are data points available of
indians migrating east west and other
places as well
so that's what happened so that is the
reason for the decline
for the apparent decline of the harappan
phase of india's civilization it is not
a separate civilization it is one of the
phases of india's history the so-called
harappan phase
but that civilization never disappeared
it still exists
it is india
the same culture exists in india we can
find evidence of the same culture five
thousand years ago in the sindh region
in the indus valley region the saraswati
valley region
another other valley or the
of that region
so the civilization did not decline and
disappear it continues it moved
elsewhere to other parts of the country
and other parts of the geography of the
subcontinent and also other places of
the other parts of the world so that's
what really happened and the cause is
climate change
rishi says why was the indus valley
civilization language different from
sanskrit and brijan says what is the
language of the saraswati valley
civilization many people are claiming
that they spoke the dravidian language
then aryans came and destroyed
everything and all that is it true
so recently people have brought to my
notice that there is some new research
paper that has come out
in which the claim is made that the
people of the saraswati sindhu region
indus valley harappan region spoke a
dravidian language
i spoke about this earlier let me speak
about it again so the claim that is made
in this research paper is that the word
for elephant in the indus valley region
was pilu
which is similar to some dravidian word
today tamil or telugu or something and
therefore they are claiming there is a
similarity and that's why this was a
dravidian language that was spoken in
the indus valley region
my question is very simple how do they
know
that the word for elephant
in the indus valley saraswati valley
region was pilu how do they know that
the word was pilu
have we been able to decipher the script
of the industry region no
nobody has successfully deciphered the
script so if we don't know what is
written in those characters how do we
know what was the word for elephant
this is incredible that people come up
with these these sort of distortions
we don't know what language was spoken
because we have not been able to
decipher the script so how can these
so-called researchers make the claim
that the word for elephant was so and so
or the word for something else was so
and so there is no logical factual
basis for any such claims these people
are charlatans
but this becomes big news all the media
reports this and now people start
believing that yeah yeah it was all
dravidian spoken in that region what
utter nonsense
absolute nonsense
we don't know
what language was spoken in that region
there is no evidence
for dravidian being spoken my gut
feeling my strong feeling uh
my educated guess is that it was
ancient sanskrit that was spoken there i
still do not have proof from all the
data points that i have
from the big picture data points from
all the evidence from so many sources it
is quite clear to me that it would have
been vedic or post vedic sanskrit that
was spoken there but i still cannot make
the claim
definitively because we don't have
unmistakable unambiguous evidence for
what the language was and therefore even
i am not claiming officially that the
language was sanskrit so how can these
people make the claim that the language
was a proto-dravidian language
absolutely not it's absolute utter
nonsense this kind of claim
and this is not the only person who has
made the claim there was this other
individual called in
who is regarded as the father of indian
linguistics who made this absolutely
asinine claim
of having translated and deciphered the
script
and i went through the
the the so-called research paper that he
published it's absolute nonsense utter
garbage what i mean he says that this
symbol means this
is stands for this word another symbol
stands for another word in tamil on what
basis did he invent these claims there
has to be some logical basis for making
the claim that so and so symbol of this
script
stands for so-and-so word in tamil on
what basis does he invent these claims
he does not give any evidence
of the logical process or the thought
process or the or the or the
justification
for assigning certain words for certain
symbols absolute nonsense he has pulled
it out of his hat
so this is the kind of distortion that
is that has been going on for the past
two centuries now we have these
brainwashed indian sepoys
these indian academic coolies
who keep on perpetuating and inventing
new ways of keeping this fake false
theory alive
ithindra says why
hasn't the indus valley civilization
language being deciphered
isn't it vedic sanskrit vedic sanskrit
is more than 10 000 bc old
etc
why do we see some other language in the
inscriptions
where these people not the descendants
of the vedic people okay what language
do we see in the inscriptions
which other language do we see in the
inscriptions we don't know right
we don't know what the inscriptions say
because we haven't been able to decipher
the script so we cannot make the claim
that there is some other language in the
inscriptions please understand that
that's point number one
secondly you are saying that the that
vedic sunscreen is more than ten
thousand bc or ten thousand twelve
thousand years old
uh how did you come to this conclusion
the oldest unambiguous evidence that we
have of sanskrit
is actually from anatolia
the methane kingdom
it's about three and a half thousand
years old
in india then we must have been writing
on paper or parchment or something and
because of our climate all that has
disintegrated or and we have not been
able to find
uh
older evidence of sanskrit in india so
thus far the oldest unmistakable
evidence undeniable evidence of sanskrit
is about three and a half thousand years
old it
is
an indication of an out of india
migration from india into anatolia
so we cannot make the claim as of today
that vedic sanskrit is more than 10 000
or 12 000 years old because we do not
possess sufficiently strong evidence for
that i am quite sure
that pre-vedic sanskrit or
proto-sanskrit must have been seven
eight nine maybe ten thousand years old
i am quite sure of that but i cannot
officially make the claim because i do
not have
hard evidence to back it up
so as of today i will not make the claim
that vedic sanskrit is 10 000 or 12 000
years old right
now the other question is why hasn't the
indus valley civilization language been
deciphered thus far the answer is very
simple because nobody has tried hard
enough first of all we do not have a lot
of
inscriptions
we have a handful of inscriptions that
have been discovered thus far
and this uh the script or the symbols
are quite
mystifying they're quite enigmatic
we're not sure if they represent
individual
letters of some alphabet
or do they
represent some syllables
of speech
or are they logo grams are the
pictograms are the hieroglyphics are the
heraldic science
we're not quite sure
and because we have so few of these
inscriptions
at hand
that's why it's it poses an even bigger
challenge in deciphering this we don't
have any other rosetta stone kind of
discovery which would put two different
languages and scripts together of the
same inscription right so we don't have
these things that's why that is one of
the reasons and secondly because people
have been trying to decipher this
half as hardly
not working together there is no funding
being being done being given to such an
effort
typically when you are trying to
decipher a script you need a team of
researchers
from different disciplines coming
together and working on it linguists
computer scientists
and other people historians all working
together
that's what you would want and for that
to happen you need
a certain amount of funding
and a long-term period of funding maybe
five years or ten years
so that can only be done when a
government or any other entity like that
will get a bunch of people together set
up an institution institute and fund all
of that
and that's not happened ever in india
because the indian government doesn't
care
and that's why we have not been able to
decipher this what needs to happen in my
opinion is we need to bring
computer science into this we need to
digitize every single inscription that
we have
we need to analyze it
using machine learning
uh algorithms and all that and
maybe that could be used to try and
figure out what it is
what sort of language does it match best
so these are some of the things that can
be done but thus far nobody has done it
because i know that
the same approach has been used to
automatically translate egyptian
hieroglyphics
machine learning algorithms so why don't
we apply this
to the
to the script of the
synthesis
we should do it but thus far nobody has
taken the initiative
nick kumar says what's the meaning of
caucasoid australoid negroid
etc why is it said that some indians are
caucasoids some are australoid so this
is
ancient obsolete race science
this is all obsolete theories okay this
is what uh
herbert hope risely
and
thomas caldwell those people would have
believed in
this is racist science race race science
they created these artificial divisions
among humans caucasoid means people who
look like europeans
australians are people who look like the
people of australia the aboriginal
people of australia negroids are the
people of africa mongolia are the people
of eastern asia et cetera they created
these rough artificial divisions and
they tried to force fit that into
everything they saw this is completely
obsolete it's completely unscientific
and yet in india people even today
believe in this
that tells you how obsolete
our education system is
and how little we actually know about
what really is happening in
in in research in historical research in
the 21st century
so caucasus means people who look like
europeans
australoid like i said all that
and according to these inch these these
19th century colonial historians
they classified the people of north
india as cockazoid
and the people of southern india is
australoids
and that is the aryan dravidian divide
so that is what these people did in
until recently or maybe even today this
may be still being taught
in india's education system which is a
which is a shame
so that essentially is what all these
false categories mean
tanveer says what is the origin or
backstory of the dravidian languages
what was the language family's
relationship with the indic languages
and sanskrit
and also the relation between its
speakers
and rohan says
what is the reason behind two language
groups in india that is sanskrit based
on and
dravidian
so once again these are categories that
have been created by foreigners
these are
completely
um
arbitrary categories they created that
fellow bishop caldwell studied one
southern indian language tamil and on
the basis of his understanding of one
language he created an entire language
family and he placed every single
southern indian language into that
family
and that is what we have been taught
as the gospel truths of indians just
can't think beyond these binaries beyond
these categories
now what is the origin of these indian
languages i think there could be what
needs to happen
is that
indian linguists
need to take an
initial look
at the indian languages
in a scientific manner
not
influenced by all these colonial ideas
and we need to cut
to formulate new categories
and new relationships
based on science and logic not based on
colonial understanding and racist
understanding that's what needs to
happen as of today there is no real
research being done in linguistics in
india linguistics is a very unscientific
field anywhere in the world today
so that's what needs to happen we are
not sure what are the origins of the
indian languages
as i demonstrated india's population is
at least 70 000 years old
in in one single geography the indian
subcontinent it's the oldest known
population group in the world and there
is very little genetic input from
outside no significant genetic input
from outside for at least the last 10 15
000 years
i think it's very clear to me that
india's languages are very very old
maybe 20 30 50 000 years possibly
and it could have happened that when the
out of africa migration took place
there were people in that small group
who spoke multiple languages multiple
ancient languages from 75 80 000 years
ago
and these people all migrated to india
and that was the original founder zone
and these ancient very ancient languages
they spoke
became the seeds
of the languages that you have today in
the world including in india and it's
clear that
tamil
is very different from sanskrit to some
extent it also has a lot of sanskrit
words in it and so on so it's a very
ancient and complicated matter
we need to try and trace back the
the roots of india's
numerous languages
the people in tamil nadu say that the
tamil is the oldest language in india
etc actually there seems to be evidence
that telugu is even older than tamil
so
we need to stop making this a
competition
i i have the strong feeling
that whether it is the sanskrit language
and it's derived in its descendant
languages
whether it is the various southern
indian eastern indian languages they
could actually originate from an out of
africa migration that happened 75 80 000
years ago
so we need to find ways of tracing that
back and that needs dedicated long-term
scientific study and an ab initio
linguistic look
into
india's languages it needs to be driven
by indian researchers young researchers
not old people old people have old ideas
get rid of them
i get rid of these old ideas not the
people
so these old ideas are all colonial
ideas we need to take a fresh look at
this
and the best way to do it is with young
researchers people who are just out of
of college or university who know the
fundamentals of linguistics who also
know the fundamentals of computer
science and all that and other sciences
and we need to start applying these
fundamentals in a
new
look
at india's language groups
so that's what needs to happen as of
today we don't have the answers to these
questions nobody has answers to the
questions of course the rn invasion
migration theorists say that they have
all the answers but they are liars they
are lying
chaitanya says what was the
proto-indo-european language was it
older than sanskrit who are the hunas
and the shakkas i will answer the first
two questions i've already answered the
third one before
what was the proto-indo-european
language so linguists western linguists
have
reconstructed
a proto-indo-european language by taking
words from all the various indian indian
and european languages and trying to
reconstruct the original words from an
older language
they call it the proto-indo-european
language they say that originally there
was only one ancient language
and one group of individuals and their
descendants went to different parts of
the world in the aryan invasion
and these different population groups
eventually developed their own daughter
languages of the proto-european language
and the oldest indian language
which is a daughter of
proto-indo-european is sanskrit vedic or
pre-vedic sanskrit so that is the theory
and they claim that certain other
languages like anatolia and et cetera
hittite etc are older than sanskrit
that's the claim they make these are all
false claims there is no real evidence
for that but they still persist in
making these claims
what do i think was the
proto-indo-european language i think it
was proto-sanskrit
the oldest known indo-european language
is sanskrit it's no other language
based on the evidence of the rigveda
which is way way way before 1500 bce
based on the evidence of the saraswati
river so clearly vedic sanskrit is the
oldest indo-european language we know of
so the proto-indo-european language has
to be proto-sanskrit the ancestor of
vedic sanskrit
which could be maybe 10 15 20 000 years
old we don't know exactly how it is i'm
just speculating
it is clearly a language that was
ancestral to vedic sanskrit
because languages keep evolving over the
centuries and millennia they just keep
evolving so if you go back 20 000 years
there will be a language that is
ancestral to sanskrit
if you go back 50 000 years there will
be an even older language which
does trace its lineage back
to sanskrit
so clearly the proto-indo european
language is proto-sanskrit obviously it
is
a language that would have been older
than sanskrit it would be the ancestral
language
of vedic sanskrit
okay we have three questions in one shan
says there is a genetic study that
claimed that the indian r1a
is the oldest genetic lineage in the
world in
oldest
indo-european genetic lineage about 18
000 years old uh the second question is
it true that r1a people who originate in
india
invaded europe and central asia that's
why all european languages and ancient
culture
has similarities with vedic hindu
akshay says we have found the oldest r1
a1a samples in india if so how old are
they
if ait is false how do why do several
indian historians push the narrative etc
okay so what is
r1a1a
that is what we need to look at let me
share my screen
with you and show what that is
uh just a second
here it is
okay so this is the geographic
distribution
of the r1a
patrilineal lineage it's called a
haplogroup what is a haplogroup a
haplogroup is a group of individuals
alive today
who all share a single genetic mutation
that traces its origin back to one
single individual who lived in the past
it's essentially an extended family
of people
so r1a
is the world's
most successful
extended family its
members most likely
exceed 1 billion individuals in
population
and its members as you can see in this
geographical distribution are everywhere
in eurasia but the highest
concentrations are in india
north of india
and
eastern europe
now this is
very closely uh
this distribution of people of r1a
origin
is very close to the distribution of
people who speak
indo-european languages
so it has been hypothesized that the
spread of this genetic lineage coincides
with the spread of the indo-european
languages and that's why some people
call it the aryan gene
now the
proponents of the aryan invasion theory
claim that this
gene i mean this this genetic mutation
originated from central asia or eastern
europe but
there is unmistakable evidence that the
highest diversity within this genetic
lineage occurs in india and it is one of
the
laws of genetics that the
geographical region where you have the
highest diversity of a haplogroup has to
be the original place where the
haplogroup originated
so other genetic studies have been
done and these genetic studies
demonstrate that the oldest evidence of
r1 is from india it's about 18 000 to 22
000 years old
which tells you that all these
individuals who live all across europe
in asia
more than one billion people today
they are all descended from one single
male
who lived somewhere in india about 18
000 years ago
that is the story
so that is the answer to this question
it's an ancient indian genetic lineage
no matter what these people claim
it's going to be debunked research base
is being done as we speak on indian
genetics and soon the research papers
will be out
and they will demonstrate that this
uh genetic lineage
originated in india and it is the indian
lineage the lineage that spread all
across
the world
so yes so these people eventually
invaded europe and central asia
and that's why that that is possibly why
indo indian and european languages are
so similar
and the culture also was once very
similar
there is another genetic lineage called
r1b
which is also very closely related to
r1a
r1 and r1a originated in india so this
other genetic lineage is called r1b like
i said it is the genetic lineage of the
yamnaya invaders of europe as you can
see there is very little of that in
india
but it's there everywhere in europe so
it looks like it is a population that
went out of india completely
and
conquered
this entire region
so very interesting genetics but we need
more research but it's clear that r1a is
very much
an indian origin genetic lineage which
kind of
debunks
the genetic components of the rn
invasion theory
blesson says
you have mentioned we don't have enough
archaeological evidence of our past
then how can we find any significant
cultural shifts how can we confidently
say that the aryans haven't invaded us
so whatever claims we make have to be on
the basis of whatever evidence is
available
we may not have sufficient evidence but
the evidence that we have points in a
certain direction and we need to take
that as the only facts we have and the
only data points we have
see the theory of general relativity
thus far has been proven
it doesn't mean tomorrow it may not be
proven it may some other theory may come
up which is better than that
as far as we know we humans
originate on planet earth
tomorrow we may find some evidence that
our ancestors may have come from mars or
elsewhere but until we find such
evidence
we cannot speculate and say that we are
not from earth
the evidence we have points to the fact
that we are all from earth and so on and
so forth so we can only make our claims
based on the evidence that is available
to us tomorrow if some new evidence
comes then we can change our perspective
and we can change our opinions
our opinions
have to match the
existing facts and the existing data
and so on the basis of all the existing
data
it is very clear that there was no aryan
invasion or migration into india
tomorrow if some other evidence comes
out
then i will change my opinion if it
shows that there was an invasion into
india i will definitely change my
opinion
i used to believe
in the are invasion theory because
that's
all what all the books said all the
writers all the historians of the
scientists said but when i examined the
hard data points i find i found it was
all a lie that's why i have changed my
opinion my opinion is not linked to my
emotions and my beliefs it is all based
on hard evidence
so tomorrow if new evidence comes out
then i will say okay there was an
innovation of india so what
but based on all the evidence today it
is clear that there was no invasion into
india the invasions and migrations went
out of india
next question is what are the oldest
evidences of horses that we find in the
indian subcontinent
we have paintings of horses and chariots
and bimbector caves and all that sonali
etc
so i have done uh i have answered this
question in detail actually
the
claim that the aryan invasion proponents
make
is that horses are not ancestral to
india they came in with the aryans and
chariots also came in with the aryans
that's the claim they make but then what
about the shivalik horse that has been
present in india for thousands of years
tens of thousands of years what about
the
cave paintings which are more than 20
000 years or at least 10 000 years old
in which there is clear depiction of
people riding horses
what about the horse pottery horse
figurines clay figurines that have been
found in the industry valley
what about the horse bones
that were found in the indus saraswati
valley region
so there are too many data points that
completely debunk this claim
that horses came into india with the rn
invaders horses have been in india for
tens of thousands of years there is
unmistakable undeniable evidence of that
so this is a completely
false claim they make
and now we have discovered evidence of a
chariot in sonoli and now these people
are claiming it's not a child it's a
bullock cart
you know what they're gonna keep on
trying to push back
but as we discover more evidence all of
these claims are going to evaporate into
thin air
that's all it is
tony says why are the baltic and slavic
languages similar to sanskrit
it's because there was an out of india
migration into europe which we can see
very clearly in all these uh
maps that that depict the various
ancient indian patrilineal lineages
whether it is r1a or r1b now obviously
genetics and languages are not linked
together today i am speaking english it
doesn't mean my genetics have changed
and they have become
genetics of the british islands
but
there seems to be a close correlation
between the spread of the
r1a and r1b haplogroups in the spread of
the indo-european languages there is
clearly some kind of linkage there so
there where out of india migrations we
know that this happened in the methane
kingdom of anatolia and other places as
well and that's why
these languages that were exported out
of india
are still
their descendants are there today in
europe whether it is the lithuanian
language latin latvian language
um
in the other baltic languages
they are in fact quite similar to
sanskrit and even the baltic culture is
quite similar to ancient indian vedic
culture for example they still
consider the horse twins the ashwins
as
a symbol of good luck as an auspicious
symbol they call it the ashwins in the
lithuanian language i think
and that is clearly a vedic
divinity
so you see lots of such
evidences of the ancient connection
between india and various parts of
europe
and obviously
the indian vedic culture is the oldest
in sanskrit is oldest and therefore the
migration must have been from india
into europe
and other parts of the world and there
are so many data points that corroborate
this
it's not rn invasion it's step migration
they became aryans after interacting
with pashupati followers that's the
claim you are making
so that is what so many people believe
but
i can debunk that in an instant
your step migrants that you are
referring to
this is what they looked my dear friend
this is what these step migrants looked
like
do they look like europeans or do they
look like indians
these are the gentlemen who invaded and
rampaged across europe and they are the
ancestors of more than 90 percent of
europe's males today
this is the step migration and invasion
you're referring to
so come on
anita says why were there no ancient
civilizations around river valleys like
ganga krishna godavari region in india
so
see it's like this
every single archaeological site we find
today
the media refers it refers to these new
sites as civilizations
they have found a new civilization in
killer d in south india
they found a new civilization somewhere
else every new archaeological site they
find they call it new civilization
which is so incredibly observed do they
even know what a civilization is
india was
one
single civilization
the indus valley civilization was not
the indus valley civilization it was the
indian civilization
and we have found evidence of even older
archaeological sites in uttar pradesh in
the ganga ganga yamuna
region we are now finding old sites even
in southern india krishna goes over a
region and so on
the reason we have not found so many
archaeological sciences because we have
not done any archaeology
in the past 70 years after independence
the only focus of india's historians and
archaeologists in the asi has been on
the mughals
and the british on restoring mughal
monuments and preserving monuments and
researching the mughals and the british
there was no focus on ancient india
and that's why we have not found thus
far
extensive evidence
of archaeological sites in all these
regions but these sites do exist it is
known
that the city of varanasi is older
than most indus valley or saraswati
valley archaeological sites it is most
likely the oldest
city we know of in the whole world
and there are so many archaeological
sites waiting to be discovered
thousands tens of thousands of
archaeological sites even in west bengal
even in northeast india in northern
india we have found indus harappan era
archaeological sites in ladakh
we have found such sites in afghanistan
and similarly in southern southern india
also once we start looking we will find
more sites but this was one single
civilization
every time you find a new village
somewhere you don't call it a new
civilization
the media is illiterate
the indian media especially
so we need to make we need to understand
that these are simply
archaeological sites look at india today
look at india today now ten thousand
five thousand years from today
let's say all indians have moved all all
humans have moved to mars because we
messed up the planet
so let's say that 5000 years from today
our descendants from mars come back to
earth to do archaeology
they find this subcontinent of india
they do some digging in the north they
find
the city which we today call delhi they
call it the north indian civilization
then they go to the south of india they
find chennai and they will call it ov
there's a southern indian civilization
south indian civilization
but we know today that delhi and chennai
are part of the same
culture the same civilization which is
indian civilization but because these
people from the future will come and
only find two data points they may
interpret it as two different
civilizations which would be incorrect
and that's the same mistake we are doing
today
we find something in
the sapta region we say it's the indus
valley civilization we find something in
west bengal we say it's a chandra ketu
civilization which signs we find
something in tamil nadu we call it the
killer civilization these are not
different civilizations
ancient india was as interconnected in
the past as india is today and the more
archaeology we do the more evidence we
are going to find about this
so these are not separate civilizations
it's the same civilization
and the reason why we have not found so
much evidence is because we have not
done any archaeology over historians and
archaeologists have been sleeping thus
far but now some some work is being done
and i'm glad to see that
parth has
a number of questions
okay so let me take question number
two
it is said that some seventy thousand
years ago a volcano erupted near
indonesia
its
ash covered the whole of india
and all the natives of this area died
and people started migrating from africa
to here
so this
volcanic eruption is called the tuba
super volcano eruption it happened about
70 75 000 years before today
in indonesia it was an enormous
volcanic explosion a super volcano
explosion you are right it's ash and
pumas covered in enormous geographical
region including much of the indian
subcontinent there is a clear there is
clear evidence of the deposition of a
layer of ash and pumice etc which is
volcanic in origin and it coincides it
coincides with the
eruption of this super volcano now
what's curious is that the stone tools
found in india
before and after this event
are identical
and therefore it's been
proven
that the people who lived in india
during this super volcano
eruption
survived this event
so it's not something some new migration
that happened into india after
the demise of the original people of
india they somehow managed to survive
this event
and the stone tools we find the
techniques used in the stone tools
are the same before and after the
eruption
so that's the thing
the people of india the ancient
people of india our ancient ancestors
survived that disastrous event
and they were most likely the
descendants of the
out of africa migration that populated
uh the known world that we know know
today
ashutosh says some people say that the
adivasi group is the natives is the
native of india is adi means beginning
and vasi means person
and so on yeah good question
so you know uh today everyone believes
that the adi vasis are the original
natives of india the original dravidians
or something and of course we
white-skinned people or or
we are in invaders are the descendants
of invaders and so on
so the word adivasi is a sanskrit
term adi means ancient vasi means a
person who lives somewhere so adivasi
means somebody who is the original or
ancient inhabitant of a particular
region
it's a sanskrit term but
this is a very recent invention this
term adivasi you will not find any
mention of the term adivasi in any
ancient literature in india
it was coined the term adivasi was
coined about 100 years ago
by the same people who are the pro
proponents of the aryan invasion theory
so it was another
technique
to try and divide the people of india
and this comes from the belief that you
know the people in the past were very
backward primitive and as
history went on people became more and
more advanced and today's humans us are
the most advanced people that ever lived
on the planet that is a very abrahamic
belief
that as you go forward in time you get
more advanced when people in the past
were more primitive this is a very
european abrahamic belief it's not an
indian belief
so this
uh
term adivasi was created to denote the
people who lived in india around 100
years ago in
small villages in in forests and so on
and they were deemed to be the original
inheritance of india but this is again
something that has no basis in fact
it has no historical basis in fact it's
a completely new term a term that was
that was coined recently and therefore
we should not take it seriously that
these are the original leaders of india
these are people who must have lived in
india for tens of thousands of years as
did everybody else
so we don't know the history of india
which happened 10 000 20 000 30 000
years ago and therefore we don't know
what happened and why what caused
certain populations to live in forests
and hills and certain populations to
live in the in the plains
of the country
it's a very old history
and maybe someday we can reconstruct it
but it is not evidence
of the aryan invasion theory
harshit says a lot of people from south
india especially tamil people believe
strongly in the arena invasion theory
and use it as a proof of tamil being
older than sanskrit and so on
and they said that they are the original
indians living in india
i don't understand this logic i know
that this justification is wrong
but this is the logic they all employ
i know
today the people of tamil nadu i mean i
know many of you are watching this i
love you all
i have absolutely nothing against
anybody against the people of south
india north india tamils davidians
so-called dravidians canada's we are all
the same people but the people of tamil
nadu are especially brainwashed i know
that i have seen it myself
they all believe that they are the
victims of a 5 000 year old conspiracy
they are an invasion and now they need
to rise up against the aryans and the
hindus and the north indians
and this is essentially separatism
this is a separatist
sentiment and this is all fomented by
the political parties especially in
tamil nadu who are extraordinarily
hindu phobic
and who are essentially separatists
many of them
are soft separatists many of them are
hard separatists they make these claims
this they they
some of them express the desire to
create a separate drawing
country out of india and so on
and and all that you know and all of
this
owes its genesis to
that individual bishop caldwell
who created this fake theory of the
dravidian language family and the rn
invasion people like max miller people
like herbert who pricely and people like
bishop caldwell who have created these
theories and all these dravidian
political parties the dmk's aid and case
they owe everything to people like
bishop caldwell and that is why they
build statues of that individual
in southern india
and
they use this theory
to justify their politics
that see politics in politics you need
victimhood you need to create divisions
only then can you create a sense of
insecurity of oppression and only then
can you say that i am the we are the
only people
who can
uh uplift you and bring you out of this
oppression that is the standard formula
in politics and that's what the
dravidian parties have been
employing for several decades
and the consequence of that is that it
has
imbued it was this this sentiment has
been infused throughout southern india
especially in tamil nadu hinduism is
being wiped out of tamil nadu
kanyakumari is full of churches the
place where lord rama
from where he went to sri lanka and all
so this is something that has been
brainwashed into the minds of the people
of southern india
and well what can i say about it it's
it's it's unfortunate
and
this situation will be rectified only
when we teach the right things
in the indian education system i am not
talking about distorting history i am
talking about decontaminating and
decolonizing history
once people learn the truth
then these political parties will lose
their relevance
they will be exposed as liars people and
then you know so that's what needs to
happen it's very unfortunate that this
sentiment is has gained so much currency
especially in tamil nadu i know i'm
going to get comments from people from
tamil nadu calling me all kinds of
things which is fine i it's not your
fault you believe all this
what we are taught during our childhood
during our formative
years
is something that remains close to our
heart forever almost
so that's how it is and people don't
like to think too much once somebody
tells you something when somebody
teaches you something you want to
cherish it for the rest of your life and
you will
not want to give that up so that's how
it is so
so what needs to happen is we need to
ensure that the newer generations
are taught clean decontaminated history
not colonial history
and then this problem may
eventually gradually be solved
because india is one culture one
civilization one people
the people of tamil nadu and the people
of northern east and western india we
are all the same people we have the same
ancestry so that's what we need to
realize
latia says when was the term aryan first
used
is it true that the
king kanishka the great called himself
aryan so the word arya means noble in
sanskrit it is not an ethnic or racial
term it is something that depends on
your behavior and your conduct in life
so a person who is civilized
refined
and essentially somebody who is a
gentleman the closest term in english is
gentlemen you know so a person of good
conduct
and good culture
was called arya now when indians went
out of india and populated persia the
persians started using arya as an ethnic
term
so the akke minute dynasty the haksha
manish dynasty the kings of the dynasty
like darayosh
kurosh
chatra and so on these kings of the
dynasty they called themselves arya or
aryans so it is there that the term arya
became an ethnic term
now kanishka the great
um
he has this ins he he created this
inscription in northern india present
day afghanistan
inscription
in which he says that i speak the arya
language so the language that koshan
spoke was
a dialect
called gandhari an ancient gandhari
dialect
it was a it was a prakrit language an
upper branch of sanskrit and kaneshka
said that this language was the arya
language
so we don't know if he used this term in
the ethnic sense or the cultural sense
maybe he meant to say that the language
we speak
is the
cultured or refined language
so we don't know exactly in what context
he used it whether he said that we are
all aryans or whether our language is a
refined language we don't know
but it is around this time that this
this term started to take on some ethnic
connotations especially in iran because
they had moved out of their ancestral
homeland of india and then they started
calling that that using that term as an
ethnic term and later on the europeans
discovered this
when they came into contact with india
and they created this fake uh
concept of an aryan race entirely and
then these white supremacists in the
nazis
they appropriated it they
misappropriated this ancient sanskrit
cultural term and they used it for
for pursuing and propagating their idea
of racial supremacy
so they are not aryans if any ethnicity
in the entire world
could be called the aryan ethnicity it
is the indo-iranian people nobody else
europeans are not aryans come on what
the hell
the word arya came from the indian
subcontinent
and it is the iranians who first used
that term
as a racial ethnic term instead of a
cultural term
and their closest
relatives living today in the entire
world are the people of the indian
subcontinent so if the term aryan is to
be used as an ethnic term
only the indo-europe indo-iranians can
be called aryans
that includes the people of present-day
india pakistan afghanistan bangladesh
persia sri lanka nepal etc nobody else
not the europeans by any means
ankur says i am from haryana i have
found many people in haryana have
brownish blonde hair color brown eyes
and white skin as of europeans this is
the case with my family whenever a baby
is born in my family he or she is blonde
i myself had blonde head in the age of
five and now they are slightly brown
however these
these features are visible in very small
percentage of the population do these
features prove the aryan invasion theory
right
if yes what was the exact location from
the aryans game
listen
india is a very large
geography a very diverse genetic
population and yet we are very similar
india has all different kinds of um
of
looks
there are so many uh recessive genes
that we find so there are many people
across india
who have blonde blondish hair if you go
to gujarat
there are many people who have green
eyes blonde hair
what's that politician shashi thorough
from kerala he has blue or green eyes
doesn't he
and so on when i mean i have brown eyes
like you say when i was a kid my hair
was it looked blonde in the sunlight
as as people grow older their hair
becomes darker anywhere in the world
including in europe
and
so these genes
that express lighter skin
or brown eyes or green eyes or blue eyes
or gray eyes
or blonde hair red hair they do exist in
india but these are called recessive
genes
it's only when a specific combination of
both parents happen
comes together that you get certain
recessive genes that become
dominant and they express themselves in
eye color skin color all that so the
overall genetics of india is like darker
skin somewhat dark hair
and brown eyes or black eyes
but you do get the other variations in
india and let me show you something very
interesting
uh
where are we
okay let me share my screen and show
something very interesting with you
all right here it is
so recently
in the past
few years in the past decade we have
discovered
that the genetic mutation that is
responsible for light skin in europeans
it originates from a single 10 000 year
old ancestor who most likely
lived
in india
okay this is one example of that
here is another such article let me show
you that
researchers traced irish fair skin back
to india and the middle east
and here is one of the
genetic genetics research papers that
talks about that
one second
let me share that
here it is the light skin allele of this
in south asians and europeans shares
identity by descent so what i mean to
say is that even the genetic
uh
even the genetic mutations responsible
for light skin
and blonde hair blue eyes etc they come
from india they originate from india we
don't realize this
so it proves actually the out of india
theory right not the rn invasion into
india theory right that is the long and
the short of it my friends
okay
uh
sanskriti says that they made this
theory without any proof the rn invasion
theory and now we have to spend our time
and energy to debunk it
don't you think we get caught in a loop
and where they keep inventing theories
out of a hat and we have to confuse we
have to refute these theories again and
again you know the only reason why i
spend my energy in my hours and my all
this time
trying to debunk this theory with all
the evidence
i don't care what the europeans and the
westerners think
i have to do it because the indians
believe in this theory
and it creates this inferiority complex
in india
indians believe that their ancestors
were wide-skinned people
they indians so many indians think that
hinduism is an evil culture that came
evil religion that came from outside
india
and sanskrit is the language of
oppressors and invaders
and all the evils in india today
are present in india because of this
evil hinduism and evil sanskrit
and the even evil brahminical people who
are in invaders
it creates this deep
sense of being ashamed of who you are it
creates this deep inferiority complex it
causes indians to regard white skin as
superior and brown skin as inferior
this is why i have spent so much time
in
putting all this evidence together to
refute this theory i don't care what the
people outside india think
it is because indians
believe in this that is why we have to
do it and that's so unfortunate
so
as as the years go by as the next two
couple of decades go by this theory is
going to be completely buried with all
the scientific evidence that is coming
out
unlike linguistics which can be
manipulated which can be politicized
science is much
more
harder
to politicize even now they are trying
to
cherry pick genetic data and all that
but
how much more how much longer can they
do that you do that
thus far there has been very little
genetic research being done
into the genetics of india into the
modern day genetics of the indian
population
once a wide scale research project is
done
on the genetics of the modern indian
population everything will be clear
so once that is done
things will be very clear and this
entire theory will be put to rest
if we have substantial and sufficient
proof that this invasion theory never
happened
why are the dogmas still being taught
into school students until today
it is to keep neocolonialism alive
india's dimensions
have an agenda
to dismantle hinduism and in sanskrit
and the indian culture
and replace it with various forms of
colonial
culture and religion
india's the majority see the indian
entire indian academic sphere has been
taken over
by marxists
and marxists are proxies for various
colonial
forces
this was done during the reign of during
the rule of the congress party and this
is a very deeply entrenched ecosystem in
india
these
marxist academicians have a stranglehold
on
the entire academic system today
so whether it is history whether it is
sociology anthropology
or any other
field of the humanities they
decide what is taught
and unfortunately the government of
india is doing nothing to change this
and that is why
these
false
and completely unscientific colonial
theories from the 19th century are still
being taught
that is the reason
okay guys this brings me to an end of
all these questions it's been almost two
hours
and therefore i will not take any live
questions today but we will continue
this in the future
so thank you very much for all your
questions i will do a presentation a
detailed presentation in the future
in which i will
put out all the details that debunk this
theory
but for now for today thank you very
much and i wish you a good night and a
good day i will see you very soon take
care
bye